South of U Street Oral History Project OHP025
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
- Series 2: Interviews
  - Alexander Padro interview (part 1 of 5), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-30.mov; 1 Files
    The first of two oral history interviews with Alexander Padro. A long-time Shaw community organizer and leader, Padro describes his involvement within the neighborhood's developments. He reflects on Shaw's history, particularly on the reasons for the 1968 riots and the effects it had on the community. He describes how urban renewal shaped Shaw after the riots, with churches and large scale housing projects leading the development of the community instead of businesses. He briefly touches on the disagreement within community groups, such as the Model Inner Cities Community Organization and the Land Redevelopment Agency, about urban renewal. Padro also speaks briefly about the crack epidemic.
  - Alexander Padro interview (part 2 of 5), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-31.mov; 1 Files
    The second of five oral history interviews with Alexander Padro. A long-time Shaw community organizer and leader, Padro describes his involvement within the neighborhood's developments. He reflects on Shaw's history, particularly on the reasons for the 1968 riots and the effects it had on the community. He describes how urban renewal shaped Shaw after the riots, with churches and large scale housing projects leading the development of the community instead of businesses. He briefly touches on the disagreement within community groups, such as the Model Inner Cities Community Organization and the Land Redevelopment Agency, about urban renewal. Padro also speaks briefly about the crack epidemic.
  - Alexander Padro interview (part 3 of 5), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-32.mov; 1 Files
    The third of five oral history interviews with Alexander Padro. A long-time Shaw community organizer and leader, Padro describes his involvement within the neighborhood's developments. He reflects on Shaw's history, particularly on the reasons for the 1968 riots and the effects it had on the community. He describes how urban renewal shaped Shaw after the riots, with churches and large scale housing projects leading the development of the community instead of businesses. He briefly touches on the disagreement within community groups, such as the Model Inner Cities Community Organization and the Land Redevelopment Agency, about urban renewal. Padro also speaks briefly about the crack epidemic.
  - Alexander Padro interview (part 4 of 5), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-33.mov; 1 Files
    The four of five oral history interviews with Alexander Padro. A long-time Shaw community organizer and leader, Padro describes his involvement within the neighborhood's developments. He reflects on Shaw's history, particularly on the reasons for the 1968 riots and the effects it had on the community. He describes how urban renewal shaped Shaw after the riots, with churches and large scale housing projects leading the development of the community instead of businesses. He briefly touches on the disagreement within community groups, such as the Model Inner Cities Community Organization and the Land Redevelopment Agency, about urban renewal. Padro also speaks briefly about the crack epidemic.
  - Alexander Padro interview (part 5 of 5), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-34.mov; 1 Files
    The fifth of five oral history interviews with Alexander Padro. A long-time Shaw community organizer and leader, Padro describes his involvement within the neighborhood's developments. He reflects on Shaw's history, particularly on the reasons for the 1968 riots and the effects it had on the community. He describes how urban renewal shaped Shaw after the riots, with churches and large scale housing projects leading the development of the community instead of businesses. He briefly touches on the disagreement within community groups, such as the Model Inner Cities Community Organization and the Land Redevelopment Agency, about urban renewal. Padro also speaks briefly about the crack epidemic.
  - Betty May Brooks-Cole interview (part 1 of 8), 2012-05; dcpl_ohp25-35.mov; 1 Files
    The first of eight oral history interviews with Betty May Brooks-Cole. In her interviews, she describes the entertainment venues for African Americans on U Street, including the Howard Theater and the Republic Theater and notes some of the musical acts that she saw perform, which included Chuck Brown and the Four Tops. She also speaks about the segregation of department stores. Brooks-Cole describes as well her fright at being on 7th street in the middle of the 1968 riots and how she felt in the aftermath of the riots.
  - Betty May Brooks-Cole interview (part 2 of 8), 2012-05; dcpl_ohp25-36.mov; 1 Files
    The second of eight oral history interviews with Betty May Brooks-Cole. In her interviews, she describes the entertainment venues for African Americans on U Street, including the Howard Theater and the Republic Theater and notes some of the musical acts that she saw perform, which included Chuck Brown and the Four Tops. She also speaks about the segregation of department stores. Brooks-Cole describes as well her fright at being on 7th street in the middle of the 1968 riots and how she felt in the aftermath of the riots.
  - Betty May Brooks-Cole interview (part 3 of 8), 2012-05; dcpl_ohp25-37.mov; 1 Files
    The third of eight oral history interviews with Betty May Brooks-Cole. In her interviews, she describes the entertainment venues for African Americans on U Street, including the Howard Theater and the Republic Theater and notes some of the musical acts that she saw perform, which included Chuck Brown and the Four Tops. She also speaks about the segregation of department stores. Brooks-Cole describes as well her fright at being on 7th street in the middle of the 1968 riots and how she felt in the aftermath of the riots.
  - Betty May Brooks-Cole interview (part 4 of 8), 2012-05; dcpl_ohp25-38.mov; 1 Files
    The fourth of eight oral history interviews with Betty May Brooks-Cole. In her interviews, she describes the entertainment venues for African Americans on U Street, including the Howard Theater and the Republic Theater and notes some of the musical acts that she saw perform, which included Chuck Brown and the Four Tops. She also speaks about the segregation of department stores. Brooks-Cole describes as well her fright at being on 7th street in the middle of the 1968 riots and how she felt in the aftermath of the riots.
  - Betty May Brooks-Cole interview (part 5 of 8), 2012-05; dcpl_ohp25-39.mov; 1 Files
    The fifth eight oral history interviews with Betty May Brooks-Cole. In her interviews, she describes the entertainment venues for African Americans on U Street, including the Howard Theater and the Republic Theater and notes some of the musical acts that she saw perform, which included Chuck Brown and the Four Tops. She also speaks about the segregation of department stores. Brooks-Cole describes as well her fright at being on 7th street in the middle of the 1968 riots and how she felt in the aftermath of the riots.
  - Betty May Brooks-Cole interview (part 6 of 8), 2012-05; dcpl_ohp25-40.mov; 1 Files
    The sixth of eight oral history interviews with Betty May Brooks-Cole. In her interviews, she describes the entertainment venues for African Americans on U Street, including the Howard Theater and the Republic Theater and notes some of the musical acts that she saw perform, which included Chuck Brown and the Four Tops. She also speaks about the segregation of department stores. Brooks-Cole describes as well her fright at being on 7th street in the middle of the 1968 riots and how she felt in the aftermath of the riots.
  - Betty May Brooks-Cole interview (part 7 of 8), 2012-05; dcpl_ohp25-41.mov; 1 Files
    The seventh of eight oral history interviews with Betty May Brooks-Cole. In her interviews, she describes the entertainment venues for African Americans on U Street, including the Howard Theater and the Republic Theater and notes some of the musical acts that she saw perform, which included Chuck Brown and the Four Tops. She also speaks about the segregation of department stores. Brooks-Cole describes as well her fright at being on 7th street in the middle of the 1968 riots and how she felt in the aftermath of the riots.
  - Betty May Brooks-Cole interview (part 8 of 8), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-42.mov; 1 Files
    The eighth of eight oral history interviews with Betty May Brooks-Cole. In her interviews, she describes the entertainment venues for African Americans on U Street, including the Howard Theater and the Republic Theater and notes some of the musical acts that she saw perform, which included Chuck Brown and the Four Tops. She also speaks about the segregation of department stores. Brooks-Cole describes as well her fright at being on 7th street in the middle of the 1968 riots and how she felt in the aftermath of the riots.
  - Ibrahim Mumin interview (part 1 of 7), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-43.mov; 1 Files
    The first of seven oral history interviews with Ibrahim Mumin. In his interviews, Mumin describes his activism during his time as a student at Howard, which attempted to push Howard to become more involved with the community. Mumin explains a sense of activism attached him to Shaw. He mentions Fides House, a community center that offered services to the Shaw community. He also touches upon the entertainment venues and restaurants he used to visit in the area. Mumin notes how his experience in activism and the confrontations it led to prepared him for the 1968 riots. Reflecting on why the riots occurred, Mumin felt that people struck out at businesses out of anger, which led to many businesses and middle-class whites fleeing the community altogether. Mumin also presents his perspective on Shaw's present and future, in terms of economics, culture, and community.
  - Ibrahim Mumin interview (part 2 of 7), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-44.mov; 1 Files
    The second of seven oral history interviews with Ibrahim Mumin. In his interviews, Mumin describes his activism during his time as a student at Howard, which attempted to push Howard to become more involved with the community. Mumin explains a sense of activism attached him to Shaw. He mentions Fides House, a community center that offered services to the Shaw community. He also touches upon the entertainment venues and restaurants he used to visit in the area. Mumin notes how his experience in activism and the confrontations it led to prepared him for the 1968 riots. Reflecting on why the riots occurred, Mumin felt that people struck out at businesses out of anger, which led to many businesses and middle-class whites fleeing the community altogether. Mumin also presents his perspective on Shaw's present and future, in terms of economics, culture, and community.
  - Ibrahim Mumin interview (part 3 of 7), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-45.mov; 1 Files
    The third of seven oral history interviews with Ibrahim Mumin. In his interviews, Mumin describes his activism during his time as a student at Howard, which attempted to push Howard to become more involved with the community. Mumin explains a sense of activism attached him to Shaw. He mentions Fides House, a community center that offered services to the Shaw community. He also touches upon the entertainment venues and restaurants he used to visit in the area. Mumin notes how his experience in activism and the confrontations it led to prepared him for the 1968 riots. Reflecting on why the riots occurred, Mumin felt that people struck out at businesses out of anger, which led to many businesses and middle-class whites fleeing the community altogether. Mumin also presents his perspective on Shaw's present and future, in terms of economics, culture, and community.
  - Ibrahim Mumin interview (part 4 of 7), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-46.mov; 1 Files
    The fourth of seven oral history interviews with Ibrahim Mumin. In his interviews, Mumin describes his activism during his time as a student at Howard, which attempted to push Howard to become more involved with the community. Mumin explains a sense of activism attached him to Shaw. He mentions Fides House, a community center that offered services to the Shaw community. He also touches upon the entertainment venues and restaurants he used to visit in the area. Mumin notes how his experience in activism and the confrontations it led to prepared him for the 1968 riots. Reflecting on why the riots occurred, Mumin felt that people struck out at businesses out of anger, which led to many businesses and middle-class whites fleeing the community altogether. Mumin also presents his perspective on Shaw's present and future, in terms of economics, culture, and community.
  - Ibrahim Mumin interview (part 5 of 7), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-47.mov; 1 Files
    The fifth of seven oral history interviews with Ibrahim Mumin. In his interviews, Mumin describes his activism during his time as a student at Howard, which attempted to push Howard to become more involved with the community. Mumin explains a sense of activism attached him to Shaw. He mentions Fides House, a community center that offered services to the Shaw community. He also touches upon the entertainment venues and restaurants he used to visit in the area. Mumin notes how his experience in activism and the confrontations it led to prepared him for the 1968 riots. Reflecting on why the riots occurred, Mumin felt that people struck out at businesses out of anger, which led to many businesses and middle-class whites fleeing the community altogether. Mumin also presents his perspective on Shaw's present and future, in terms of economics, culture, and community.
  - Ibrahim Mumin interview (part 6 of 7), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-48.mov; 1 Files
    The sixth of seven oral history interview with Ibrahim Mumin. In his interviews, Mumin describes his activism during his time as a student at Howard, which attempted to push Howard to become more involved with the community. Mumin explains a sense of activism attached him to Shaw. He mentions Fides House, a community center that offered services to the Shaw community. He also touches upon the entertainment venues and restaurants he used to visit in the area. Mumin notes how his experience in activism and the confrontations it led to prepared him for the 1968 riots. Reflecting on why the riots occurred, Mumin felt that people struck out at businesses out of anger, which led to many businesses and middle-class whites fleeing the community altogether. Mumin also presents his perspective on Shaw's present and future, in terms of economics, culture, and community.
  - Ibrahim Mumin interview (part 7 of 7), 2012-06; dcpl_ohp25-49.mov; 1 Files
    The seventh of seven oral history interviews with Ibrahim Mumin. In his interviews, Mumin describes his activism during his time as a student at Howard, which attempted to push Howard to become more involved with the community. Mumin explains a sense of activism attached him to Shaw. He mentions Fides House, a community center that offered services to the Shaw community. He also touches upon the entertainment venues and restaurants he used to visit. Mumin notes how his experience in activism and the confrontations it led to prepared him for the 1968 riots. Reflecting on why the riots, Mumin feels that people struck out at businesses out of anger, which led to many businesses and middle-class whites fleeing the community altogether. Mumin also presents his perspective on Shaw's present and future, in terms of economics, culture, and community.